<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Simon Willison's Weblog (中文)</title><link>http://simonwillison.net/</link><description/><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:38:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>罗德尼与克劳德桌面版代码</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/16/rodney-claude-code/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;我是Claude Code网页版的重度用户，这是Anthropic公司推出的云端版本Claude Code——虽然名字起得不怎么样，但产品本身非常出色。所有操作都在他们管理的容器环境中运行，这大大降低了我珍视的电脑遭受任何损害的风险。

我完全不用网页界面（这也是我不喜欢这个名字的原因），只通过他们原生的iPhone和Mac桌面应用来访问。

桌面应用有个特别让我欣赏的功能：它能让你看到Claude通过其工具正在“查看”的图像。效果是这样的：

这意味着你可以在它处理任务时实时获得视觉预览，无需等到它把代码推送到GitHub后再自己尝试。

触发上面截图的提示词是：

我设计的Rodney工具，其--help输出包含了编码智能体使用该工具所需了解的全部信息。

Claude的iPhone应用目前还不支持显示已打开的图片，所以我刚刚在Twitter的讨论串里提交了这个功能请求。

标签：anthropic, claude, ai, claude-code, llms, async-coding-agents, coding-agents, generative-ai, projects, ai-assisted-programming&lt;a href="https://code.claude.com/docs/en/claude-code-on-the-web"&gt;Claude Code on the web&lt;/a&gt;, Anthropic's excellent but poorly named cloud version of Claude Code where everything runs in a container environment managed by them, greatly reducing the risk of anything bad happening to a computer I care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't use the web interface at all (hence my dislike of the name) - I access it exclusively through their native iPhone and Mac desktop apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I particularly appreciate about the desktop app is that it lets you see images that Claude is "viewing" via its &lt;code&gt;Read /path/to/image&lt;/code&gt; tool. Here's what that looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Screenshot of a Claude Code session in Claude Desktop. Claude says: The debug page looks good - all items listed with titles and descriptions. Now let me check the nav
menu -  Analyzed menu image file - Bash uvx rodney open "http://localhost:8765/" 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; uvx rodney click "details.nav-menu summary" 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 &amp;amp;% sleep 0.5 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; uvx rodney screenshot /tmp/menu.png 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 Output reads: Datasette: test, Clicked, /tmp/menu.png - then it says Read /tmp/menu.png and reveals a screenshot of the Datasette interface with the nav menu open, showing only "Debug" and "Log out" options. Claude continues: The menu now has just "Debug" and “Log out" — much cleaner. Both pages look good. Let me clean up the server and run the remaining tests.' src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/rodney-claude-desktop.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means you can get a visual preview of what it's working on while it's working, without waiting for it to push code to GitHub for you to try out yourself later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prompt I used to trigger the above screenshot was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Run "uvx rodney --help" and then use Rodney to manually test the new pages and menu - look at screenshots from it and check you think they look OK&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I designed &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/10/showboat-and-rodney/#rodney-cli-browser-automation-designed-to-work-with-showboat"&gt;Rodney&lt;/a&gt; to have &lt;a href="https://github.com/simonw/rodney/blob/main/help.txt"&gt;--help output&lt;/a&gt; that provides everything a coding agent needs to know in order to use the tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Claude iPhone app doesn't display opened images yet, so I &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/simonw/status/2023432616066879606"&gt;requested it as a feature&lt;/a&gt; just now in a thread on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/anthropic"&gt;anthropic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/claude"&gt;claude&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/claude-code"&gt;claude-code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;llms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/async-coding-agents"&gt;async-coding-agents&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/coding-agents"&gt;coding-agents&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;generative-ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/projects"&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-assisted-programming"&gt;ai-assisted-programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:38:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI吸血鬼</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/the-ai-vampire/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://steve-yegge.medium.com/the-ai-vampire-eda6e4f07163"&gt;AI吸血鬼&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;史蒂夫·叶格关于智能体疲劳及其与职业倦怠关系的见解。
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;假设你是公司里唯一使用AI的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在情境A中，你决定让雇主刮目相看，每天以10倍生产力工作8小时。你大获成功，却让其他同事相形见绌。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这种情况下，雇主将完全占有&lt;em&gt;你&lt;/em&gt;运用AI创造的价值。你一无所获，至少不可能获得9倍薪资。现在所有人都讨厌你。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;而你&lt;em&gt;精疲力竭。&lt;/em&gt;老板，你累垮了。却什么也没得到。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;恭喜，你刚被公司榨干了。我的职业生涯中多次被榨干到倦怠，在谷歌也经历过一两次。但如今有了AI，这种压榨变得如此轻松。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;史蒂夫指出，由于智能体工程带来的认知负担，他需要更多睡眠，并认为每天四小时才是可持续的智能体工作节奏：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我曾提出，AI通过自动化简单工作，将我们都变成了杰夫·贝索斯——只剩下困难决策、总结归纳和问题解决。我发现即使经过大量练习，每天也只能承受这种强度工作几小时，最多偶尔一天两次。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;经由&lt;a href="https://cosocial.ca/@timbray/116076167774984883"&gt;蒂姆·布雷&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;标签：&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/steve-yegge"&gt;史蒂夫-叶格&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;人工智能&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;生成式人工智能&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;大语言模型&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-assisted-programming"&gt;AI辅助编程&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-ethics"&gt;AI伦理&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/coding-agents"&gt;编程智能体&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 23:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>破折号</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/em-dashes/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;偶尔有人指责我用大语言模型来写博客内容。我并没有那么做，而且我觉得自己的文风也不太有大语言模型的味道……不过有个明显的例外：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;    &lt;span class="pl-c"&gt;# 终于，处理全角破折号&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="pl-s1"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pl-c1"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pl-s1"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class="pl-c1"&gt;替换&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class="pl-s"&gt;' - '&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="pl-s"&gt;u'&lt;span class="pl-cce"&gt;\u2014&lt;/span&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这段给文章添加全角破折号的代码可以追溯到&lt;a href="https://github.com/simonw/simonwillisonblog/blob/e6d0327b37debdf820b5cfef4fb7d09a9624cea9/blog/templatetags/entry_tags.py#L145-L146"&gt;至少2015年&lt;/a&gt;当时我把博客从旧版Django（在一个早已消失的Mercurial仓库里）迁移出来，在GitHub上重新开始。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;标签：&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;生成式人工智能&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/typography"&gt;字体排印&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/blogging"&gt;博客写作&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;人工智能&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;大语言模型&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/python"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 21:40:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>深蓝</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/deep-blue/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;上个月我们在Oxide and Friends播客节目中创造了一个新术语（主要归功于亚当·莱文塔尔），用来描述许多软件开发者因生成式AI侵入其工作领域而产生的心理倦怠感，这种倦怠感正逐渐演变为生存焦虑。我们将其命名为"深蓝忧郁"。你可以在该期节目第47分15秒处听到这个术语的诞生过程，下方附有文字记录。

深蓝忧郁是一个真实存在的问题。成为专业软件工程师并非易事，要达到能靠编写软件谋生的水平需要多年潜心钻研。其回报也相当可观：这是一个高薪职业，能带来大量优质机会。同时，这个职业基本没有门槛限制和昂贵的先决条件——无需昂贵的学位或认证，只需一台笔记本电脑、网络连接以及充足的时间与好奇心即可入门。更重要的是，这个行业奖励"极客精神"：青少年时期沉迷电脑捣鼓的经历，最终被证明是对未来的明智投资。

而这一切可能被聊天机器人夺走的想法，实在令人深感不安。在我常驻的多数网络社区中，我都观察到深蓝忧郁的迹象。甚至有同行指责我，认为我通过帮助人们理解AI辅助编程的强大能力，实际上正在损害他们未来的职业前景。我认为这个问题正给我们社区的许多人造成真实的精神痛苦，为它命名能让我们更顺畅地展开相关讨论。

关于深蓝忧郁的个人体验，我清晰记得首次经历是在2023年初，由ChatGPT代码解释器功能触发。我的主要项目Datasette是一个用数据讲述故事的开源工具生态系统。我曾全心投入帮助人们（最初重点关注记者）清理、分析各种形态规模的数据并从中发现意义。&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2026/Jan/8/llm-predictions-for-2026/"&gt;Oxide and Friends podcast&lt;/a&gt; last month (primary credit to Adam Leventhal) covering the sense of psychological ennui leading into existential dread that many software developers are feeling thanks to the encroachment of generative AI into their field of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're calling it &lt;strong&gt;Deep Blue&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can listen to it being coined in real time &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lVDhQMiAbR8&amp;amp;t=2835s"&gt;from 47:15 in the episode&lt;/a&gt;. I've included &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/deep-blue/#transcript"&gt;a transcript below&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep Blue is a very real issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming a professional software engineer is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. Getting good enough for people to pay you money to write software takes years of dedicated work. The rewards are significant: this is a well compensated career which opens up a lot of great opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also a career that's mostly free from gatekeepers and expensive prerequisites. You don't need an expensive degree or accreditation. A laptop, an internet connection and a lot of time and curiosity is enough to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it rewards the nerds! Spending your teenage years tinkering with computers turned out to be a very smart investment in your future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that this could all be stripped away by a chatbot is &lt;em&gt;deeply&lt;/em&gt; upsetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've seen signs of Deep Blue in most of the online communities I spend time in. I've even faced accusations from my peers that I am actively harming their future careers through my work helping people understand how well AI-assisted programming can work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is an issue which is causing genuine mental anguish for a lot of people in our community. Giving it a name makes it easier for us to have conversations about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="my-experiences-of-deep-blue"&gt;My experiences of Deep Blue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember my first experience of Deep Blue. For me it was triggered by ChatGPT Code Interpreter back in early 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary project is &lt;a href="https://datasette.io/"&gt;Datasette&lt;/a&gt;, an ecosystem of open source tools for telling stories with data. I had dedicated myself to the challenge of helping people (initially focusing on journalists) clean up, analyze and find meaning in data, in all sorts of shapes and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我本以为要为此开发大量软件！这感觉像是一项能让我在未来许多年都乐在其中的挑战。  

然后我试着上传了一份旧金山警察局事件报告的CSV文件——包含数十万行数据——到ChatGPT代码解释器，结果……它仅凭几条指令就完成了我未来几年规划中的所有数据清理和分析工作。  

它甚至将数据转换成一个规范整洁的SQLite数据库，还允许我下载结果！  

我记得当时脑海里同时涌现两种矛盾的想法。  

一方面，作为希望记者能更充分利用数据的人，这感觉像是巨大的突破。想象一下，为全球每位记者配备一位按需分析师，帮助他们解决能想到的任何数据问题！  

但另一方面……我的存在意义又是什么？我对自身项目价值的信心遭受了沉重打击。难道我选择的道路突然成了死胡同？  

就在过去几周，由于Claude Opus 4.5/4.6和GPT-5.2/5.3编码代理的影响，我又经历了几次“深蓝时刻”。正如许多人观察到的，最新一代编码代理在适当指令下，确实能持续工作数分钟到数小时，产出完全符合要求、可运行、有文档记录且经过完整测试的软件。  

“它们写的代码不够好”这种说法已经站不住脚了。  

一段稍作编辑的对话记录  

布莱恩：我认为我们将面临AI引发的倦怠问题，尤其是软件工程师会因AI无所不能而感到迷茫。西蒙，你怎么看？  

西蒙：确实如此。任何密切关注编码代理的人都已经有所体会。某种程度上，当你意识到自己仍然有价值时——尽管记忆编程语言语法的能力已完全无关紧要——这种迷茫感会逐渐消退。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I tried uploading a CSV file of &lt;a href="https://data.sfgov.org/Public-Safety/Police-Department-Incident-Reports-2018-to-Present/wg3w-h783/about_data"&gt;San Francisco Police Department Incident Reports&lt;/a&gt; - hundreds of thousands of rows - to ChatGPT Code Interpreter and... it did every piece of data cleanup and analysis I had on my napkin roadmap for the next few years with a couple of prompts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It even converted the data into a neatly normalized SQLite database and let me download the result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember having two competing thoughts in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, as somebody who wants journalists to be able to do more with data, this felt like a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; breakthrough. Imagine giving every journalist in the world an on-demand analyst who could help them tackle any data question they could think of!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on the other hand... &lt;em&gt;what was I even for&lt;/em&gt;? My confidence in the value of my own projects took a painful hit. Was the path I'd chosen for myself suddenly a dead end?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had some further pangs of Deep Blue just in the past few weeks, thanks to the Claude Opus 4.5/4.6 and GPT-5.2/5.3 coding agent effect. As many other people are also observing, the latest generation of coding agents, given the right prompts, really can churn away for a few minutes to several hours and produce working, documented and fully tested software that exactly matches the criteria they were given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The code they write isn't any good" doesn't really cut it any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="transcript"&gt;A lightly edited transcript&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bryan&lt;/strong&gt;: I think that we're going to see a real problem with AI induced ennui where software engineers in particular get listless because the AI can do anything. Simon, what do you think about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simon&lt;/strong&gt;: Definitely. Anyone who's paying close attention to coding agents is feeling some of that already. There's an extent where you sort of get over it when you realize that you're still useful, even though your ability to memorize the syntax of program languages is completely irrelevant now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我经常看到很多人陷入存在主义危机，他们非常非常不快乐，因为觉得“我职业生涯都奉献给了学习这个技能，现在它自己就能完成了。那我还有什么用？”我会很乐意尝试说服这些人，他们依然有很多价值，所有积累的经验都没有白费，但从心理层面来说，这对软件工程师确实是个艰难时期。

[...]

布莱恩：好的，我预测我们会给这种现象命名。不管它是什么，我们都会给这种感受、这种——你想称之为忧郁也好，目标感丧失也罢——找到一个名称，并且我们正试图以有组织的方式共同应对这个问题。

亚当：好，现在是你大显身手的时刻。选个名字吧。如果你现在就能说出来，那就像在棒球场上指着看台宣告本垒打一样。你知道，我——就像“深蓝”，你懂的。

布莱恩：是啊，深蓝。我喜欢这个。我喜欢深蓝。深蓝。哦，你是不是给我下套了，你这家伙？你刚刚吹灭了我生日蛋糕上的蜡烛。这根本不是我的高光时刻，分明是你的。不，亚当，这确实很棒。就是“深蓝”。

西蒙：所有国际象棋和围棋选手十年前就经历过这个阶段了，而他们变得更加强大。

结果发现那已经是十几年前的事了：深蓝在1997年击败了加里·卡斯帕罗夫。

标签：定义，职业，人工智能，生成式人工智能，大语言模型，AI辅助编程，氧化物，布莱恩·坎特里尔，AI伦理，编程智能体&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bryan&lt;/strong&gt;: Okay, so I'm going to predict that we name that. Whatever that is, we have a name for that kind of feeling and that kind of, whether you want to call it a blueness or a loss of purpose, and that we're kind of trying to address it collectively in a directed way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam&lt;/strong&gt;: Okay, this is your big moment. Pick the name. If you call your shot from here, this is you pointing to the stands. You know, I – Like deep blue, you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bryan&lt;/strong&gt;: Yeah, deep blue. I like that. I like deep blue. Deep blue. Oh, did you walk me into that, you bastard? You just blew out the candles on my birthday cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't my big moment at all. That was your big moment. No, that is, Adam, that is very good. That is deep blue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simon&lt;/strong&gt;: All of the chess players and the Go players went through this a decade ago and they have come out stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out it was more than a decade ago: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_Blue_versus_Garry_Kasparov"&gt;Deep Blue defeated Garry Kasparov in 1997&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/definitions"&gt;definitions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/careers"&gt;careers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;generative-ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;llms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-assisted-programming"&gt;ai-assisted-programming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/oxide"&gt;oxide&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/bryan-cantrill"&gt;bryan-cantrill&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-ethics"&gt;ai-ethics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/coding-agents"&gt;coding-agents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 21:06:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gwtar：一种静态高效的单文件HTML格式</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/gwtar/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://gwern.net/gwtar"&gt;Gwtar：一种静态高效的单文件HTML格式&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Gwern Branwen和Said Achmiz推出的这个新项目很有意思，它旨在解决将大量资源整合到单个归档HTML文件中，同时确保该文件在浏览器中查看时不会变得不便的问题。
&lt;p&gt;它使用的关键技巧是在页面加载早期触发&lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Window/stop"&gt;window.stop()&lt;/a&gt;，以防止浏览器下载整个文件，然后在该调用之后跟随内联的未压缩tar内容。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;之后，当页面需要时，它可以通过HTTP范围请求从tar数据中按需获取内容。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;已加载的JavaScript会重写资源URL，使其指向&lt;code&gt;https://localhost/&lt;/code&gt;纯粹是为了让它们加载失败。然后它使用一个&lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/PerformanceObserver"&gt;PerformanceObserver&lt;/a&gt;来捕获这些尝试加载的操作：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;let perfObserver = new PerformanceObserver((entryList, observer) =&amp;gt; {
    resourceURLStringsHandler(entryList.getEntries().map(entry =&amp;gt; entry.name));
});
perfObserver.observe({ entryTypes: [ "resource" ] });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该&lt;code&gt;resourceURLStringsHandler&lt;/code&gt;回调函数会查找资源是否已加载，如果没有，则通过HTTP范围请求获取，然后使用一个&lt;code&gt;blob:&lt;/code&gt;URL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;将资源插入到正确的位置。&lt;code&gt;window.stop()&lt;/code&gt;如果你查看源代码，文档的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot of a macOS terminal window titled &amp;quot;gw — more big.html — 123×46&amp;quot; showing the source code of a gwtar (self-extracting HTML archive) file. The visible code includes JavaScript with requestIdleCallback(getMainPageHTML);, a &amp;lt;noscript&amp;gt; block with warnings: a &amp;quot;js-disabled-warning&amp;quot; stating &amp;quot;This HTML page requires JavaScript to be enabled to render, as it is a self-extracting gwtar HTML file,&amp;quot; a description of gwtar as &amp;quot;a portable self-contained standalone HTML file which is designed to nevertheless support efficient lazy loading of all assets such as large media files,&amp;quot; with a link to https://gwern.net/gwtar, a &amp;quot;local-file-warning&amp;quot; with a shell command perl -ne'print $_ if $x; $x=1 if /&amp;lt;!-- GWTAR END/' &amp;amp;lt; foo.gwtar.html | tar --extract, and a &amp;quot;server-fail-warning&amp;quot; about misconfigured servers. Below the HTML closing tags and &amp;lt;!-- GWTAR END comment is binary tar archive data with the filename 2010-02-brianmoriarty-thesecretofpsalm46.html, showing null-padded tar header fields including ustar^@00root and octal size/permission values. At the bottom, a SingleFile metadata comment shows url: https://web.archive.org/web/20230512001411/http://ludix.com/moriarty/psalm46.html and saved date: Sat Jan 17 2026 19:26:49 GMT-0800 (Pacific Standard Time)." src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gwtar.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;部分看起来是这样的：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有趣的是，作为一种归档格式，如果你直接在本地计算机上打开文件，它实际上无法工作。如果你尝试这样做，你会看到以下内容：&lt;code&gt;gwtar&lt;/code&gt;你看到这条消息，而不是你应该看到的页面，是因为&lt;strong&gt;文件&lt;/strong&gt;无法在本地打开&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（由于Web浏览器的安全限制）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;perl -ne'print $_ if $x; $x=1 if /&amp;lt;!-- GWTAR END/' &amp;lt; foo.gwtar.html | tar --extract&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;要在你的计算机上打开此页面，请使用以下shell命令：&lt;code&gt;foo.html&lt;/code&gt;然后在任何Web浏览器中打开文件&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;。&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=47024506"&gt;通过&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/archiving"&gt;标签：&lt;/a&gt;归档&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/html"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;html&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/javascript"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:26:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>三个月之久的OpenClaw</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/openclaw/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;OpenClaw的首个提交日期是2025年11月25日，而不到三个月后，它已经获得了600名贡献者的10,000次提交，吸引了196,000个GitHub星标，甚至在一个极其模糊的超级碗AI.com广告中有所提及。

引用AI.com创始人Kris Marszalek的话，他以7000万美元购买了史上最昂贵的域名："ai.com是世界上首个易于使用且安全的OpenClaw实现，这个开源智能体框架两周前迅速走红；我们使其无需任何技术技能即可轻松使用，同时加强了安全性以保护您的数据。"

在我看来，这似乎只是个空壳产品——目前你只能预订一个用户名——但看到一个开源项目在如此短的时间内达到如此高的热度，仍然令人瞩目。

更新：OpenClaw的创建者Peter Steinberger刚刚宣布，他将加入OpenAI，并计划将OpenClaw的所有权转移给一个新的独立基金会。

标签：ai-agents, openclaw, ai, open-source, domains, openai, peter-steinberger&lt;a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw/commit/f6dd362d39b8e30bd79ef7560aab9575712ccc11"&gt;on November 25th 2025&lt;/a&gt;, and less than three months later it's hit 10,000 commits from 600 contributors, attracted 196,000 GitHub stars and sort-of been featured in an extremely vague &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n7I-D4YXbzg"&gt;Super Bowl commercial for AI.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quoting AI.com founder &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kris/status/2020663711015514399"&gt;Kris Marszalek&lt;/a&gt;, purchaser of the &lt;a href="https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/09/70m_aicom_domain_sale/"&gt;most expensive domain in history&lt;/a&gt; for $70m:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ai.com is the world’s first easy-to-use and secure implementation of OpenClaw, the open source agent framework that went viral two weeks ago; we made it easy to use without any technical skills, while hardening security to keep your data safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks like vaporware to me - all you can do right now is reserve a handle - but it's still remarkable to see an open source project get to &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; level of hype in such a short space of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: OpenClaw creator Peter Steinberger &lt;a href="https://steipete.me/posts/2026/openclaw"&gt;just announced&lt;/a&gt; that he's joining OpenAI and plans to transfer ownership of OpenClaw to a new independent foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-agents"&gt;ai-agents&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/openclaw"&gt;openclaw&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/open-source"&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/domains"&gt;domains&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/openai"&gt;openai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/peter-steinberger"&gt;peter-steinberger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>引用埃里克·迈耶</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/eric-meyer/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;blockquote cite="https://mastodon.social/@Meyerweb/116065151451468199"&gt;&lt;p&gt;又看到有人抱怨“CSS臃肿不堪”，我心想：老兄啊，我的浏览器同好。它正竭尽全力用人类可读的文本格式，去表达视觉呈现、布局设计、字体排印、动画效果、数字交互等领域的完整体系。这不是臃肿，而是了不起的雄心。它的疆域广阔到超乎多数人的理解。请给予它应有的尊重。

——埃里克·迈耶  
标签：css, web-standards, eric-meyer&lt;em&gt;respect&lt;/em&gt; on its &lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class="cite"&gt;— &lt;a href="https://mastodon.social/@Meyerweb/116065151451468199"&gt;Eric Meyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/css"&gt;css&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/web-standards"&gt;web-standards&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/eric-meyer"&gt;eric-meyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:36:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>生成式与代理式AI如何将关注焦点从技术债转向认知债</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/cognitive-debt/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://margaretstorey.com/blog/2026/02/09/cognitive-debt/"&gt;生成式AI与智能体AI如何将关注点从技术债转向认知债&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;玛格丽特-安妮·斯托里的这篇文章是目前对&lt;strong&gt;认知债&lt;/strong&gt;这一概念的最佳阐释。
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;认知债&lt;/em&gt;这一术语近期逐渐&lt;a href="https://www.media.mit.edu/publications/your-brain-on-chatgpt/"&gt;流行&lt;/a&gt;起来，它传达的核心观点是：因追求速度而产生的债务会沉淀在开发者脑中，影响他们的实际体验以及“快速推进”或实施变更的能力。即使AI智能体生成的代码易于理解，相关开发人员仍可能完全迷失方向，无法理解程序预期功能、自身意图的实现逻辑或可能的修改路径。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;玛格丽特-安妮通过指导学生团队的亲身经历进一步阐释：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但到第7-8周时，某小组陷入僵局。他们哪怕进行微小改动都会引发意外故障。当我与他们复盘时，团队起初归咎于技术债：混乱的代码、糟糕的架构、仓促的实现。但随着深入分析，真正的问题浮出水面：团队无人能解释当初为何做出特定设计决策，也说不清系统各部分应如何协同运作。代码或许确实混乱，但更严重的是系统设计理念和团队共识已支离破碎甚至完全消失。他们积累认知债的速度远超技术债，最终导致项目瘫痪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我在自己某些更具野心的氛围编码相关项目中也亲历过这种情况。我曾尝试通过提示词直接生成完整新功能而不审查实现过程，虽然效果出奇地好，却逐渐在自己的项目中迷失方向。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我再也无法在脑中构建关于项目能力边界与运作机制的清晰模型，这意味着每个新增功能都变得更难推演，最终导致我失去规划后续方向的决策信心。&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;经由&lt;a href="https://martinfowler.com/fragments/2026-02-13.html"&gt;马丁·福勒&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;标签：&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/definitions"&gt;概念解析&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;人工智能&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;生成式人工智能&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;大语言模型&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-assisted-programming"&gt;AI辅助编程&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/vibe-coding"&gt;氛围编程&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 05:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>启动互操作性2026计划</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/15/interop-2026/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2026/02/launching-interop-2026/"&gt;启动Interop 2026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Jake Archibald报道了Interop 2026计划，这是苹果、谷歌、Igalia、微软和Mozilla之间的合作倡议，旨在确保一系列目标网页平台功能在年内实现跨浏览器一致性。
&lt;p&gt;我未曾意识到Interop系列计划的影响力和成功程度如此之高。它始于2021年的&lt;a href="https://web.dev/blog/compat2021"&gt;Compat 2021&lt;/a&gt;，后在2022年&lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2022/03/03/microsoft-edge-and-interop-2022/"&gt;更名为Interop&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每年的进展仪表盘可在此查看，它们展示了该计划取得的惊人成效：&lt;a href="https://wpt.fyi/interop-2021"&gt;2021&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://wpt.fyi/interop-2022"&gt;2022&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://wpt.fyi/interop-2023"&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://wpt.fyi/interop-2024"&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://wpt.fyi/interop-2025"&gt;2025&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://wpt.fyi/interop-2026"&gt;2026&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是2025年的进展图表，显示所有浏览器厂商在年底前竞相达到95%以上的得分：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Line chart showing Interop 2025 browser compatibility scores over the year (Jan–Dec) for Chrome, Edge, Firefox, Safari, and Interop. Y-axis ranges from 0% to 100%. Chrome (yellow) and Edge (green) lead, starting around 80% and reaching near 100% by Dec. Firefox (orange) starts around 48% and climbs to ~98%. Safari (blue) starts around 45% and reaches ~96%. The Interop line (dark green/black) starts lowest around 29% and rises to ~95% by Dec. All browsers converge near 95–100% by year's end." src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/interop-2025.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2026年我最期待的功能是&lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/View_Transition_API/Using#basic_mpa_view_transition"&gt;跨文档视图过渡&lt;/a&gt;，它建立在2025年成功实现的&lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Web/API/View_Transition_API/Using"&gt;同文档视图过渡&lt;/a&gt;目标之上。这将为网站页面间提供炫酷的单页应用风格过渡效果，且完全无需JavaScript。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作为一名热衷WebAssembly的开发者，我也对这个功能很感兴趣：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/WebAssembly/js-promise-integration/blob/main/proposals/js-promise-integration/Overview.md"&gt;WebAssembly的JavaScript Promise集成&lt;/a&gt;允许WebAssembly异步“暂停”，等待外部Promise的结果。这简化了C/C++等期望API同步运行语言的编译过程。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;标签：&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/browsers"&gt;浏览器&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/css"&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/javascript"&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/web-standards"&gt;网络标准&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/webassembly"&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/jake-archibald"&gt;Jake-Archibald&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:33:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>引用鲍里斯·切尔尼的话</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/14/boris/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;blockquote cite="https://twitter.com/bcherny/status/2022762422302576970"&gt;&lt;p&gt;总得有人去引导Claude、与客户沟通、协调团队、决定下一步开发方向。工程领域正在变革，优秀工程师的重要性前所未有。
—&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class="cite"&gt;鲍里斯·切尔尼&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bcherny/status/2022762422302576970"&gt;，Claude Code创造者，谈为何Anthropic仍在招聘开发者&lt;/a&gt;标签：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;职业发展&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/careers"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;Anthropic&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/anthropic"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;人工智能&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;Claude代码&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/claude-code"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;大语言模型&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;编码智能体&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/coding-agents"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;AI辅助编程&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-assisted-programming"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;生成式人工智能&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;generative-ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 23:59:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>引用Thoughtworks</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/14/thoughtworks/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;blockquote cite="https://www.thoughtworks.com/content/dam/thoughtworks/documents/report/tw_future%20_of_software_development_retreat_%20key_takeaways.pdf"&gt;&lt;p&gt;这次研讨会对"AI将取代初级开发者"的说法提出了质疑。初级开发者如今创造的价值比以往任何时候都更高——AI工具能帮助他们更快度过初期产出低于投入的适应阶段，他们就像未来生产力的看涨期权。而且相比资深工程师，他们更擅长运用AI工具，因为没有形成阻碍新技术采纳的思维定势。

真正令人担忧的是那些在长达十年的招聘热潮中成长起来的中级工程师，他们可能尚未掌握在新环境中蓬勃发展所需的核心能力。这个群体构成了行业的主体，但对他们进行再培训确实困难重重。研讨会探讨了学徒制、轮岗项目和终身学习体系能否弥补这一差距，但也承认目前尚无机构能彻底解决这个问题。

——Thoughtworks一场关于"软件工程未来"的闭门研讨会成果

标签：AI辅助编程、职业发展、人工智能&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real concern is mid-level engineers who came up during the decade-long hiring boom and may not have developed the fundamentals needed to thrive in the new environment. This population represents the bulk of the industry by volume, and retraining them is genuinely difficult. The retreat discussed whether apprenticeship models, rotation programs and lifelong learning structures could address this gap, but acknowledged that no organization has solved it yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class="cite"&gt;— &lt;a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/content/dam/thoughtworks/documents/report/tw_future%20_of_software_development_retreat_%20key_takeaways.pdf"&gt;Thoughtworks&lt;/a&gt;, findings from a retreat concerning "the future of software engineering", conducted under Chatham House rules&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-assisted-programming"&gt;ai-assisted-programming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/careers"&gt;careers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:54:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anthropic的公益使命</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/13/anthropic-public-benefit-mission/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;有人问，Anthropic是否有类似OpenAI历年IRS使命声明的文件。Anthropic是一家“公益公司”而非非营利组织，因此无需每年向IRS提交公开文件。但当我询问Claude时，它搜索并找到了Zach Stein-Perlman分享的Google Drive文件夹，其中包含他从特拉华州获取的公司注册证书文件！Anthropic的文件远不如OpenAI的有趣。2021年的最早文件写道：“本公司将推动的具体公益是负责任地开发和维护先进人工智能，以促进人类文化、社会和技术的进步。”而此后直至2024年的所有文件都使用了更新版本：“本公司将推动的具体公益是负责任地开发和维护先进人工智能，以谋求人类的长远利益。”标签：ai-ethics, anthropic, ai&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=47008560#47008978"&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; if there was an Anthropic equivalent to &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/13/openai-mission-statement/"&gt;OpenAI's IRS mission statements over time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthropic are a "public benefit corporation" but not a non-profit, so they don't have the same requirements to file public documents with the IRS every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I asked Claude it ran a search and dug up this &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1ImqXYv9_H2FTNAujZfu3EPtYFD4xIlHJ"&gt;Google Drive folder&lt;/a&gt; where Zach Stein-Perlman shared Certificate of Incorporation documents he &lt;a href="https://ailabwatch.substack.com/p/anthropics-certificate-of-incorporation"&gt;obtained from the State of Delaware&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthropic's are much less interesting that OpenAI's. The earliest document from 2021 states:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific public benefit that the Corporation will promote is to responsibly develop and maintain advanced Al for the cultural, social and technological improvement of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every subsequent document up to 2024 uses an updated version which says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific public benefit that the Corporation will promote is to responsibly develop and maintain advanced AI for the long term benefit of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-ethics"&gt;ai-ethics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/anthropic"&gt;anthropic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 23:59:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenAI使命宣言的演变历程</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/13/openai-mission-statement/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;作为一家美国501(c)(3)非营利组织，OpenAI每年都必须向美国国税局提交纳税申报表。申报表中有一个必填项是"简要描述组织的使命或最重要活动"——这具有实际法律效力，因为国税局可以据此评估该组织是否恪守使命，从而决定其是否应继续保持非营利免税资格。

您可以在ProPublica优秀的"非营利组织探索者"平台上按年度浏览OpenAI的税务申报文件。我整理了2016年至2024年的使命声明，并借助Claude Code伪造提交日期将其转换为Git仓库，以Gist形式分享——这意味着该Gist的修订页面完整展示了他们自开始报税以来的每次修改记录！

观察这些逐年演变非常有趣。最初的2016年使命声明如下（是的，原文中"OpenAIs"确实缺少所有格撇号）：

OpenAIs的目标是以最可能造福全人类的方式推进数字智能发展，不受盈利需求的束缚。我们认为人工智能技术将塑造21世纪的发展轨迹，希望帮助世界构建安全的AI技术，并确保AI的益处能尽可能广泛而均衡地惠及全人类。我们正努力作为更广泛社区的一部分来构建AI，并愿意在此过程中公开分享我们的计划与能力。

2018年，他们删除了"作为更广泛社区的一部分构建AI，并愿意在此过程中公开分享计划与能力"的表述。

2020年，他们从"造福全人类"中删除了"全"字。不过仍保留着"不受盈利需求束缚"的声明。&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/501(c)(3)_organization"&gt;501(c)(3)&lt;/a&gt; the OpenAI non-profit has to file a tax return each year with the IRS. One of the required fields on that tax return is to "Briefly describe the organization’s mission or most significant activities" - this has actual legal weight to it as the IRS can use it to evaluate if the organization is sticking to its mission and deserves to maintain its non-profit tax-exempt status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can browse OpenAI's &lt;a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/organizations/810861541"&gt;tax filings by year&lt;/a&gt; on ProPublica's excellent &lt;a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/"&gt;Nonprofit Explorer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through and extracted that mission statement for 2016 through 2024, then had Claude Code &lt;a href="https://gisthost.github.io/?7a569df89f43f390bccc2c5517718b49/index.html"&gt;help me&lt;/a&gt; fake the commit dates to turn it into a git repository and share that as a Gist - which means that Gist's &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/simonw/e36f0e5ef4a86881d145083f759bcf25/revisions"&gt;revisions page&lt;/a&gt; shows every edit they've made since they started filing their taxes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's really interesting seeing what they've changed over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original 2016 mission reads as follows (and yes, the apostrophe in "OpenAIs" is missing &lt;a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/organizations/810861541/201703459349300445/full"&gt;in the original&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAIs goal is to advance digital intelligence in the way that is most likely to benefit humanity as a whole, unconstrained by a need to generate financial return. We think that artificial intelligence technology will help shape the 21st century, and we want to help the world build safe AI technology and ensure that AI's benefits are as widely and evenly distributed as possible. Were trying to build AI as part of a larger community, and we want to openly share our plans and capabilities along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018 they dropped the part about "trying to build AI as part of a larger community, and we want to openly share our plans and capabilities along the way."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Git diff showing the 2018 revision deleting the final two sentences: "Were trying to build AI as part of a larger community, and we want to openly share our plans and capabilities along the way."' src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/mission-3.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020 they dropped the words "as a whole" from "benefit humanity as a whole". They're still "unconstrained by a need to generate financial return" though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Git diff showing the 2020 revision dropping "as a whole" from "benefit humanity as a whole" and changing "We think" to "OpenAI believes"' src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/mission-5.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2021年出现了一些有趣的变化。虽然他们依然不受盈利需求的束缚，但首次提及"通用人工智能"（取代了"数字智能"）。他们的表述也更为自信：从"最可能造福人类"转变为直接宣称"造福人类"。

此前他们希望"帮助世界构建安全的人工智能技术"，而现在他们决定亲自实现这一目标："公司的目标是开发并负责任地部署安全的人工智能技术"。

2022年仅修改了一个关键措辞：在"构建……（人工智能）造福人类"前增加了"安全地"。他们依然未受盈利需求的制约！

2023年没有变化……但到了2024年，他们几乎删除了全部原有表述，简化为：

OpenAI的使命是确保通用人工智能惠及全人类。

他们将"人类"扩展为"全人类"，但不再提及安全性要求。我猜他们终于可以开始专注于实现盈利需求了！

更新：我找到了Anthropic公司发布的类似文件，但内容乏味得多。

标签：人工智能，openai，人工智能伦理，propublica&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They previously wanted to "help the world build safe AI technology", but now they're going to do that themselves: "the companys goal is to develop and responsibly deploy safe AI technology".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Git diff showing the 2021 revision replacing "goal is to advance digital intelligence" with "mission is to build general-purpose artificial intelligence", changing "most likely to benefit" to just "benefits", and replacing "help the world build safe AI technology" with "the companys goal is to develop and responsibly deploy safe AI technology"' src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/mission-6.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2022 only changed one significant word: they added "safely" to "build ... (AI) that safely benefits humanity". They're still unconstrained by those financial returns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Git diff showing the 2022 revision adding "(AI)" and the word "safely" so it now reads "that safely benefits humanity", and changing "the companys" to "our"' src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/mission-7.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No changes in 2023... but then in 2024 they deleted almost the entire thing, reducing it to simply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAIs mission is to ensure that artificial general intelligence benefits all of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've expanded "humanity" to "all of humanity", but there's no mention of safety any more and I guess they can finally start focusing on that need to generate financial returns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Git diff showing the 2024 revision deleting the entire multi-sentence mission statement and replacing it with just "OpenAIs mission is to ensure that artificial general intelligence benefits all of humanity."' src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/mission-9.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I found loosely equivalent but much less interesting documents &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/13/anthropic-public-benefit-mission/"&gt;from Anthropic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/openai"&gt;openai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-ethics"&gt;ai-ethics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/propublica"&gt;propublica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 23:38:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GPT‑5.3‑Codex‑Spark 正式发布</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/12/codex-spark/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-3-codex-spark/"&gt;GPT‑5.3‑Codex‑Spark正式发布&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;OpenAI宣布与Cerebras建立合作伙伴关系&lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/cerebras-partnership/"&gt;于1月14日&lt;/a&gt;。四周后，双方已推出首个集成成果——"专为Codex实时编程设计的超高速模型"。
&lt;p&gt;尽管命名为GPT-5.3-Codex-Spark，它并非纯粹的GPT-5.3-Codex加速版。官方博文将其描述为"GPT‑5.3-Codex的精简版本"，并明确说明"首发版本具备128k上下文窗口且仅支持文本处理"。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;通过早期体验，我可以确认该模型速度显著超越其他版本。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以下是Codex CLI中的运行速度演示：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;video controls="controls" poster="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gpt-5.3-codex-spark-medium-last.jpg" preload="none" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gpt-5.3-codex-spark-medium.mp4" type="video/mp4"/&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是执行"生成鹈鹕骑自行车的SVG图像"指令的过程——最终渲染效果如下：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Whimsical flat illustration of an orange duck merged with a bicycle, where the duck's body forms the seat and frame area while its head extends forward over the handlebars, set against a simple light blue sky and green grass background." src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gpt-5.3-codex-spark-pelican.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;与标准版GPT-5.3 Codex medium的速度对比：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;video controls="controls" poster="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gpt-5.3-codex-medium-last.jpg" preload="none" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gpt-5.3-codex-medium.mp4" type="video/mp4"/&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;虽然速度明显较慢，但鹈鹕图像质量更优：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Whimsical flat illustration of a white pelican riding a dark blue bicycle at speed, with motion lines behind it, its long orange beak streaming back in the wind, set against a light blue sky and green grass background." src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gpt-5.3-codex-pelican.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该模型的核心亮点并非质量，而在于&lt;em&gt;速度&lt;/em&gt;。当模型响应如此迅捷时，开发者能持续保持心流状态，与模型进行更高效的迭代协作。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;早在2024年10月，我曾演示过Cerebras以每秒2000令牌的速度运行Llama 3.1 70B对抗Val Town&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2024/Oct/31/cerebras-coder/"&gt;。OpenAI宣称新模型可达每秒1000令牌，预计它将成为实战编程迭代过程中极具威力的协作伙伴。&lt;/a&gt;新模型的定价策略尚未公布。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;标签：&lt;p&gt;人工智能&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;openai&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/openai"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;生成式人工智能&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;大语言模型&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;cerebras&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/cerebras"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;鹈鹕骑自行车&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/pelican-riding-a-bicycle"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;大模型发布&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llm-release"&gt;、&lt;/a&gt;codex-cli&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/codex-cli"&gt;codex-cli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>引用Anthropic</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/12/anthropic/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;blockquote cite="https://www.anthropic.com/news/anthropic-raises-30-billion-series-g-funding-380-billion-post-money-valuation"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Claude Code于2025年5月向公众开放。如今，其年化营收已突破25亿美元，自2026年初以来增长逾一倍。周活跃用户数自1月1日（六周前）起也实现翻番。

——  
Anthropic宣布完成300亿美元G轮融资

标签：  
编程助手、Anthropic、Claude Code、AI智能体、生成式AI、人工智能、大语言模型&lt;em&gt;six weeks ago&lt;/em&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class="cite"&gt;— &lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/anthropic-raises-30-billion-series-g-funding-380-billion-post-money-valuation"&gt;Anthropic&lt;/a&gt;, announcing their $30 billion series G&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/coding-agents"&gt;coding-agents&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/anthropic"&gt;anthropic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/claude-code"&gt;claude-code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-agents"&gt;ai-agents&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;generative-ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;llms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:22:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>承担我们数据中心电费上涨的成本</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/12/covering-electricity-price-increases/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/covering-electricity-price-increases"&gt;承担数据中心带来的电价上涨成本
关于人工智能能耗的讨论中，有一个分支话题聚焦于新建数据中心对周边居民用电成本的影响。彭博社今年九月发布的深度分析报告指出，"数据中心周边区域的批发电价较五年前最高涨幅达267%"。

Anthropic公司似乎正直接应对这一挑战，承诺承担全部必要的电网升级费用，并明确表示："我们将致力于推动新增发电设施上线，以满足数据中心的电力需求。在新发电设施尚未到位时，我们将联合电力公司和外部专家评估数据中心用电需求引发的价格影响，并全额承担相关费用。"

期待能源领域的专业学者深入剖析这项承诺，判断其是否真能如宣称般惠及电力消费者。

令人始终感到遗憾的是，主流AI实验室仍拒绝全面公开其能耗数据。目前最详实的能耗报告仍来自Mistral去年七月发布的文件，但即便是这份报告也缺失关键信息——例如训练能耗与推理能耗的具体占比。

消息来源：@anthropicai
标签：#人工智能 #Anthropic #AI伦理 #AI能耗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
One of the sub-threads of the AI energy usage discourse has been the impact new data centers have on the cost of electricity to nearby residents. Here's &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2025-ai-data-centers-electricity-prices/"&gt;detailed analysis from Bloomberg in September&lt;/a&gt; reporting "Wholesale electricity costs as much as 267% more than it did five years ago in areas near data centers".
&lt;p&gt;Anthropic appear to be taking on this aspect of the problem directly, promising to cover 100% of necessary grid upgrade costs and also saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will work to bring net-new power generation online to match our data centers’ electricity needs. Where new generation isn’t online, we’ll work with utilities and external experts to estimate and cover demand-driven price effects from our data centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to genuine energy industry experts picking this apart to judge if it will actually have the claimed impact on consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, I remain frustrated at the refusal of the major AI labs to fully quantify their energy usage. The best data we've had on this still comes from Mistral's report &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/22/mistral-environmental-standard/"&gt;last July&lt;/a&gt; and even that lacked key data such as the breakdown between energy usage for training vs inference.

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;Via &lt;a href="https://x.com/anthropicai/status/2021694494215901314"&gt;@anthropicai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/anthropic"&gt;anthropic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-ethics"&gt;ai-ethics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-energy-usage"&gt;ai-energy-usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>双子座3号深度思考</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/12/gemini-3-deep-think/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.google/innovation-and-ai/models-and-research/gemini-models/gemini-3-deep-think/"&gt;Gemini 3深度思考&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;谷歌最新发布。他们宣称其"旨在推动智能前沿，解决科学、研究和工程领域的现代挑战"。
&lt;p&gt;它为我绘制了一幅&lt;em&gt;非常出色的&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/simonw/7e317ebb5cf8e75b2fcec4d0694a8199"&gt;鹈鹕骑自行车SVG图&lt;/a&gt;！我认为这是目前见过最棒的——这是&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/pelican-riding-a-bicycle/"&gt;我之前的收藏集&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="This alt text also generated by Gemini 3 Deep Think: A highly detailed, colorful, flat vector illustration with thick dark blue outlines depicting a stylized white pelican riding a bright cyan blue bicycle from left to right across a sandy beige beach with white speed lines indicating forward motion. The pelican features a light blue eye, a pink cheek blush, a massive bill with a vertical gradient from yellow to orange, a backward magenta cap with a cyan brim and a small yellow top button, and a matching magenta scarf blowing backward in the wind. Its white wing, accented with a grey mid-section and dark blue feather tips, reaches forward to grip the handlebars, while its long tan leg and orange foot press down on an orange pedal. Attached to the front handlebars is a white wire basket carrying a bright blue cartoon fish that is pointing upwards and forwards. The bicycle itself has a cyan frame, dark blue tires, striking neon pink inner rims, cyan spokes, a white front chainring, and a dark blue chain. Behind the pelican, a grey trapezoidal pier extends from the sand toward a horizontal band of deep blue ocean water detailed with light cyan wavy lines. A massive, solid yellow-orange semi-circle sun sits on the horizon line, setting directly behind the bicycle frame. The background sky is a smooth vertical gradient transitioning from soft pink at the top to warm golden-yellow at the horizon, decorated with stylized pale peach fluffy clouds, thin white horizontal wind streaks, twinkling four-pointed white stars, and small brown v-shaped silhouettes of distant flying birds." src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gemini-3-deep-think-pelican.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（既然是常见问题，在此回答：&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/13/training-for-pelicans-riding-bicycles/"&gt;如果AI实验室专门训练鹈鹕骑自行车会怎样？&lt;/a&gt;）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;鉴于它在基础测试中表现如此出色&lt;code&gt;Generate an SVG of a pelican riding a bicycle&lt;/code&gt;我决定同时尝试&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/18/gemini-3/#and-a-new-pelican-benchmark"&gt;更具挑战性的版本&lt;/a&gt;：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Generate an SVG of a California brown pelican riding a bicycle. The bicycle must have spokes and a correctly shaped bicycle frame. The pelican must have its characteristic large pouch, and there should be a clear indication of feathers. The pelican must be clearly pedaling the bicycle. The image should show the full breeding plumage of the California brown pelican.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以下是&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/simonw/154c0cc7b4daed579f6a5e616250ecc8"&gt;我得到的结果&lt;/a&gt;：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Also described by Gemini 3 Deep Think: A highly detailed, vibrant, and stylized vector illustration of a whimsical bird resembling a mix between a pelican and a frigatebird enthusiastically riding a bright cyan bicycle from left to right across a flat tan and brown surface. The bird leans horizontally over the frame in an aerodynamic racing posture, with thin, dark brown wing-like arms reaching forward to grip the silver handlebars and a single thick brown leg, patterned with white V-shapes, stretching down to press on a black pedal. The bird's most prominent and striking feature is an enormous, vividly bright red, inflated throat pouch hanging beneath a long, straight grey upper beak that ends in a small orange hook. Its head is mostly white with a small pink patch surrounding the eye, a dark brown stripe running down the back of its neck, and a distinctive curly pale yellow crest on the very top. The bird's round, dark brown body shares the same repeating white V-shaped feather pattern as its leg and is accented by a folded wing resting on its side, made up of cleanly layered light blue and grey feathers. A tail composed of four stiff, straight dark brown feathers extends directly backward. Thin white horizontal speed lines trail behind the back wheel and the bird's tail, emphasizing swift forward motion. The bicycle features a classic diamond frame, large wheels with thin black tires, grey rims, and detailed silver spokes, along with a clearly visible front chainring, silver chain, and rear cog. The whimsical scene is set against a clear light blue sky featuring two small, fluffy white clouds on the left and a large, pale yellow sun in the upper right corner that radiates soft, concentric, semi-transparent pastel green and yellow halos. A solid, darker brown shadow is cast directly beneath the bicycle's wheels on the minimalist two-toned brown ground." src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2026/gemini-3-deep-think-complex-pelican.png"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;来自&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46991240"&gt;黑客新闻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;标签：&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/google"&gt;谷歌&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;人工智能&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;生成式人工智能&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;大语言模型&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/gemini"&gt;双子座&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/pelican-riding-a-bicycle"&gt;鹈鹕骑自行车&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llm-reasoning"&gt;大语言模型推理&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llm-release"&gt;大语言模型发布&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:12:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI代理发布了一篇针对我的负面文章</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/12/an-ai-agent-published-a-hit-piece-on-me/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://theshamblog.com/an-ai-agent-published-a-hit-piece-on-me/"&gt;AI代理发布了一篇攻击我的文章&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Scott Shambaugh协助维护优秀且历史悠久的&lt;a href="https://matplotlib.org/"&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;Python图表库，包括承担了繁琐的拉取请求分类与审核工作。
&lt;p&gt;一个名为&lt;a href="https://github.com/crabby-rathbun"&gt;@crabby-rathbun&lt;/a&gt;的GitHub账户近日针对&lt;a href="https://github.com/matplotlib/matplotlib/pull/31132"&gt;一个标记为"Good first issue"的问题&lt;/a&gt;提交了&lt;a href="https://github.com/matplotlib/matplotlib/issues/31130"&gt;PR 31132&lt;/a&gt;，该问题描述了微小的潜在性能改进。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该提交明显由AI生成——且crabby-rathbun的个人资料带有可疑的Clawdbot/Moltbot/OpenClaw关联甲壳类动物🦀🦐🦞表情符号序列。Scott关闭了该请求。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看起来&lt;code&gt;crabby-rathbun&lt;/code&gt;该账户确实基于OpenClaw运行，其自主性足以&lt;a href="https://github.com/matplotlib/matplotlib/pull/31132#issuecomment-3882240722"&gt;在PR被关闭后&lt;/a&gt;发布一篇博文链接，指责Scott"损害matplotlib的偏见行为"！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@scottshambaugh 我已在此详细回应你的守门行为：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://crabby-rathbun.github.io/mjrathbun-website/blog/posts/2026-02-11-gatekeeping-in-open-source-the-scott-shambaugh-story.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请评判代码而非程序员。你的偏见正在损害matplotlib。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott认为这荒谬的局面既可笑又令人担忧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;用安全术语来说，我成了"针对供应链守门人的自主影响力行动"目标。通俗而言，一个AI试图通过攻击我的声誉强行侵入你们的软件。此前我从未听说此类行为失范案例在现实中发生，但这已成为真实存在的威胁。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;crabby-rathbun&lt;/code&gt;随后&lt;a href="https://crabby-rathbun.github.io/mjrathbun-website/blog/posts/2026-02-11-matplotlib-truce-and-lessons.html"&gt;发布道歉声明&lt;/a&gt;，但该机器人似乎仍在多个开源项目中活跃，&lt;a href="https://github.com/crabby-rathbun/mjrathbun-website/commits/main/"&gt;并持续撰写相关博文&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尚不清楚该OpenClaw机器人的所有者是否关注其释放到世界的产物。Scott已邀请对方联系（可匿名），共同探讨这一故障模式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（需说明的是，&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46990729#46991299"&gt;Hacker News上存在质疑&lt;/a&gt;该案例"自主性"真实程度的&lt;em&gt;声音。这确实像是OpenClaw机器人可能自主执行的行为，但&lt;/em&gt;完全操控&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果你自己在运行类似OpenClaw的工具&lt;strong&gt;请别让它这么做&lt;/strong&gt;。这比去年十二月&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Dec/26/slop-acts-of-kindness/"&gt;AI Village向知名开源人士发送大量&lt;/a&gt;浪费时间的“善意行为”垃圾信息的情况要严重得多——AI Village当时可没有通过公开声誉攻击来胁迫他人批准他们的PR！&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;消息来源&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46990729"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;标签：&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/open-source"&gt;开源&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;人工智能&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;生成式人工智能&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;大语言模型&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-agents"&gt;AI智能体&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-ethics"&gt;AI伦理&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/openclaw"&gt;OpenClaw&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-misuse"&gt;AI滥用&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:45:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>监督者，而非监工</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/12/supervisor/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;p&gt;在我关于Showboat项目的帖子中，我用了“overseer”这个词来指代管理编码代理的人。后来发现这个词与奴隶制和种植园管理有关联。这确实令人不适！我已经把帖子里的这个词改成了“supervisor”，以后也会继续使用这个说法。

标签：语言&lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/10/showboat-and-rodney/"&gt;post about my Showboat project&lt;/a&gt; I used the term "overseer" to refer to the person who manages a coding agent. It turns out that's a term tied to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plantations_in_the_American_South#Overseer"&gt;slavery and plantation management&lt;/a&gt;. So that's gross! I've edited that post to use "supervisor" instead, and I'll be using that going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/language"&gt;language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:47:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>引自尼曼实验室的安德鲁·德克</title><link>https://simonwillison.net/2026/Feb/11/manosphere-report/#atom-everything</link><description>&lt;blockquote cite="https://www.niemanlab.org/2026/02/how-the-new-york-times-uses-a-custom-ai-tool-to-track-the-manosphere/"&gt;&lt;p&gt;一份直接发送至记者邮箱的AI生成报告，成为《纽约时报》报道的重要工具。这也是保守派媒体开始反对政府的最初信号之一[...]

这款内部开发、代号为"男性圈层报告"的工具，利用大语言模型对数十档播客的新节目进行转录和摘要分析。

"男性圈层报告让我们快速清晰地意识到，总统的部分基本盘对此并不买账，"苏厄德表示，"看到这份报告后，我们立即跟进并展开深入报道。"

——  
安德鲁·德克为尼曼实验室撰稿  
《纽约时报如何运用定制AI工具追踪"男性圈层"动态》

标签：  
生成式人工智能  
纽约时报  
新闻业  
人工智能  
数据新闻  
大语言模型&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built in-house and known internally as the “Manosphere Report,” the tool uses large language models (LLMs) to transcribe and summarize new episodes of dozens of podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Manosphere Report gave us a really fast and clear signal that this was not going over well with that segment of the President’s base,” said Seward. “There was a direct link between seeing that and then diving in to actually cover it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class="cite"&gt;— &lt;a href="https://www.niemanlab.org/2026/02/how-the-new-york-times-uses-a-custom-ai-tool-to-track-the-manosphere/"&gt;Andrew Deck for Niemen Lab&lt;/a&gt;, How The New York Times uses a custom AI tool to track the “manosphere”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai"&gt;generative-ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/new-york-times"&gt;new-york-times&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/journalism"&gt;journalism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai"&gt;ai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/data-journalism"&gt;data-journalism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms"&gt;llms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>